

Pudongxin District, Shanghai, China

 $\square \ (+86) \ 131-6701-7220 \ | \ \blacksquare \ 77qingliu@gmail.com \ | \ \blacktriangleleft \ www.77qingliu.com \ | \ \boxdot \ 77qingliu \ | \ \boxdot \ 77qingliu$ 

"Be the change that you want to see in the world."

## Summary.

3 years experience specializing in statistical analysis, data mining using SAS/Python/SQL. Proficient in data process, data analysis, statistical modeling as well as programming languages such as SAS, Python. Familiar with Probability theory and mathematical statistics and basic statistical methods such as Statistical Testing, Linear Regression, Logistic Regression, Bayesian Method, Survival Analysis, etc. Fundamental knowledge of machine learning algorithms such as support vector machines, decision trees, neural networks, and clustering, etc. Master data structure and basic algorithm. Particularly interested in data science and computer science, especially data mining, data analysis, machine learning, and programming languages such as Python, R, SAS. Strong dedication and pursuit of technology, good self-learning ability, good at learning and studying the latest research results.

# Work Experience

Eli Lilly & Company Shanghai, China

Statistical Analyst

• Routine work includes creating robust programs to import, analyze, interpret and report data from Clinical Trial for regulatory submissions, and manuscripts, as well as for communicating with key colleagues. Organize and analyze data for patterns, trends and strategic insights in supporting medical research and drug development.

- Acting as leading statistical analyst, Cooperate with the market department, analyze drug marketing data with survival model, find trending and strategic insights through data analysis, received LCDDMAC Excellence Award.
- Acting as leading statistical analyst, Cooperate with Health Outcome team, analyze the reliability and validity of disease measurement scale
  among Chinese populations. and Logistic regression analysis was used to analyze factors that influencing the occurrence the disease, published
  three papers/manuscripts.
- Implement open source technology (eg. Python, R) to drive innovation, automate the process of data analysis and improve work efficiency, avoid tedious work and save working time.

PAREXEL International Shanghai, China

STATISTICAL PROGRAMMER

Jun. 2015 - Dov. 2016

Nov. 2016 - PRESENT

- Production of well-formatted datasets(SDTM, ADaM) and table, listing, figures using SAS software for Phase I-IV trials and FDA submissions.
- Building complex and reusable programs to automate the process of Data Cleaning, Validation, Analysis and Report generation.

#### Presentation & Publication

PharmaSUG China 2017 Shanghai, China

Presenter Jul. 2017

• Streamline Table Lookup by Embedding HASH in FCMP

#### **Neuropsychiatric Disease and Treatment**

Worldwide

AUTHOR

Jan. 2018

 Reliability and validity of the Chinese version of questionnaire—Children with Difficulties for Chinese Children or Adolescents with Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder: a cross-sectional survey

# **Open Sourced Projects**

**SAS-Syntax-and-Theme** A SAS syntax highlighting package powered by regex in Sublime Text 3(download up to 4K)

**Algorithms** Data Structure/Algorithms implemented in Python

**AutoGenaCRF** A set of SAS macros strove to automatically generate aCRF for FDA submission.

### Skills

**Programming** SAS, Python(Proficient). R, C(Knowledgeble)

**Data Science** Statistical Analysis, Statistical Modeling, Data Manipulate, Data Visualization, Machine Learning

Languages English, Chinese

## **Honors & Awards**

2017 **LCDDMAC Excellence Award**, Eli Lilly & Company

2015 **Outstanding Graduate**, Huazhong University of Science and Technology

Shanghai, China Wuhan, China

# **Education**

#### **HUST(Huazhong University of Science and Technology)**

B.S. IN PREVENTIVE MEDICINE

Wuhan, China

Sep. 2010 - Jun. 2015

• Core Curriculum: Health Statistics , Epidemiology, Multivariate Statistics

#### **East China Normal University**

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Shanghai, China

Reading